Finding Aid for Kathryn C. Nye papers, 1952-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kathryn C. Nye papers
1952-1967
Nye, Kathryn C.
85332 Aa 2
Recording secretary of the Central Committee of the Michigan Democratic Party, 1962-1967. Correspondence, working files, printed material, photographs and audio-tapes dealing with the organization and management of the state Democratic Party, Lansing and Ingham County, Michigan, party politics, various political issues, Michigan participation in the national Democratic Conventions of 1960 and 1964, and the Michigan Senate Campaign of 1966.
3.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Kathryn C. Nye (donor no. 5801 ) and came to the library in February 1976.
The collection is open to research.
Kathryn C. Nye of East Lansing, Michigan was recording secretary of the Michigan Democratic Party State Central Committee from 1962 to 1967.
The Nye papers, though containing virtually no personal material, is strong on state Democratic politics, especially as relates to her work as recording secretary and her involvement in party affairs in Lansing and Ingham County.
The collection has been arranged into the following series: Personal / Biographical; Correspondence; Lansing and Ingham County Democratic Party; Michigan Democratic Party; Party Conventions; Miscellaneous Democratic Party materials. The collection documents her political activities on the local, county, and state level and includes memoranda and correspondence with three Democratic state chairmen: Neil Staebler, John Joe Collins, and Zolton Ferency. In addition, her files include State Central Committee minutes, directories and other information on party publications, such as the Democratic Digest. Her files also contain material on various political campaigns of the 1950's and 1960's, and on various national Democratic Conventions, including notes and tape recordings of the meetings of the Michigan caucus at the 1964 convention.
Subjects:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Elections--Michigan--1966.; Ingham County (Mich.); Lansing (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; United States--Politics and government--1961-1963.; Women in politics--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Families.; Hart, Adelaide, 1900-; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Hart family.; Living rooms.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Moody family.; Nye, Kathryn C.; Staebler, Neil, 1905-2000; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Women.
Contributors:
Ferency, Zolton A., 1922-1993; Staebler, Neil, 1905-2000; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal / Biographical
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Presidential inaugural memorabilia, 1961; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Undated, 1952-1967; 27 folders (Box 1)
- Lansing and Ingham County Democratic Party
  - Lansing Democratic Party
    - Precinct and ward breakdowns (Box 1)
    - Precinct records (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous lists of wards (Box 1)
  - Lansing Township Telephone campaign (Box 1)
  - East Lansing Democratic Club by-laws (Box 1)
  - Ingham County Democratic Party Committee Organization
    - By-laws (Box 1)
    - Members (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1958; 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Proposals (Box 1)
    - Resolutions (Box 1)
  - Ingham County Democratic Party
    - Convention, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Directory, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Delegates to state Convention, 1964; 1967 (Box 1)
    - Campaign strategy, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Voter identification program, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Financial report, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Contributors to Stevenson Campaign, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Women, 1956; 1963-1967 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter: Democrat of Ingham County, 1966 (Box 1)
- Michigan Democratic Party
  - County chair materials
    - Officers (Box 1)
    - Leadership workshop (Box 1)
    - Leaders reference book (Box 1)
    - Publicity chairmen, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Committee performance, 1950-1951; 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - Progress, 1946-1966 (Box 1)
    - Voting statistics, 1952-1964 (Box 1)
  - State Central Committee.
    - Structure (Box 2)
    - By-laws (Box 2)
    - Functions (Box 2)
    - Job Classification (Box 2)
    - Attendance records, 1956; 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, undated (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1956-1963 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, January-July 1966 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, August-December 1966 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Biennial report, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Committees, 1953; 1965 (Box 2)
    - Subcommittees, 1957; 1959 (Box 2)
    - Nationalities branch (Box 2)
    - Policy Committee (Box 2)
    - Legislative liaison committee (Box 2)
    - Information service notes (Box 2)
    - Information service correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
    - Information service speakers bureau, 1955-1964 (Box 2)
    - Information service miscellanea (Box 2)
    - Finance campaign (Box 2)
    - Finance correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - Finance records, 1953-1967 (Box 2)
  - Campaigns and election material
    - Directory, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Directory, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Proposed changes in election code, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Lists of candidates, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Campaign coordinating committee notes, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Cavanagh Senate campaign, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Hart Senate campaign, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Williams Senate campaign, 1966 (Box 2)
    - How to organize the Democratic Party (Box 2)
    - "Get-out-the-vote," registration, 1954-1958; 1966 (Box 2)
    - "Get-out-the-vote," telephone contact, 1956; 1958 (Box 2)
    - "Get-out-the-vote," election (Box 2)
    - "People-win-elections, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Party membership drive (Box 2)
    - Contributors to Michigan Democratic Party, 1955 (Box 2)
    - Legislative Information for Teamwork, 1960-1965 (Box 3)
    - Planning group for legislative conferences, minutes (Box 3)
    - Proposal for establishing Democratic Advisory Council (Box 3)
  - Campaign issues
    - Miscellaneous issues (Box 3)
    - Agriculture, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Democratic committee on agriculture, minutes, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Atoms for Peace (Box 3)
    - Civil liberties, 1959; 1967 (Box 3)
    - Civil rights, 1953; 1956-1957; 1966 (Box 3)
    - Consumer protection (Box 3)
    - Education, 1954-1957; 1961-1965 (Box 3)
    - Finance, 1957-1959 (Box 3)
    - Foreign policy, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
    - Housing, 1953; 1965 (Box 3)
    - Labor, 1955; 1966 (Box 3)
    - Ombudsman, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Poverty, 1965 (Box 3)
    - Tax legislation, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
    - Platforms and resolutions, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
    - Democratic platforms and issues, 1956-1957; 1965-1967 (Box 3)
- Party Conventions
  - Michigan State Democratic Conventions
    - Organization (Box 3)
    - Convention papers, 1964-1967 (Box 3)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 3)
      - 1966 (Box 3)
      - 1967 (Box 3)
  - Four state Democratic conference, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Midwest Democratic conference, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Democratic National Convention
    - Michigan delegates, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Michigan caucus minutes, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Convention papers, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Convention papers, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Michigan caucus minutes, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Michigan caucus meeting, 1964; 6 audiotapes (Box 3)
    - Rules and procedures, 1964 (Box 3)
    - News bulletin (Box 3)
    - Delegate reform, 1965 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Democratic Party
  - Publications (miscellaneous) (Box 3)
  - Democratic Digest
    - Quotas, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1955; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1956; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Instructions and contents (Box 3)
  - Michigan Democrats directory, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Democratic women directory (Box 4)
  - Young Democrats (Box 4)
  - Democratic women's organizations (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Democratic Party
  - Church involvement in Michigan Politics, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Political activity of classified employees in state government (Box 4)
  - Resolutions to support Democratic Party (Box 4)
  - Problems of Democratic Party (Box 4)
  - Sympathetic resolutions (Box 4)
  - John F. Kennedy House (Box 4)
  - Extremist literature, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Speech by Adlai Stevenson at Jefferson-Jackson Day Meeting, March 10, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning John Hannah's chairmanship of Civil Rights Commission, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Clippings, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4)